coloradomesa.edu 2019-12-15

# Privacy Statement

Privacy Statement
Commitment to Individual Privacy
Colorado Mesa University is committed to protecting the privacy and accuracy of confidential information submitted by
employees, students and visitors to our Web site. However, because Colorado Mesa University is a public institution,
some personally identifiable information may be subject to disclosure pursuant to the Colorado Open Records Act (C.R.S.
§ 24-72-101 et seq.).
Colorado Open Records Act (C.R.S. § 24-72-101 et seq.)
The State of Colorado requires that all public records be open for public inspection by any person except as otherwise
provided by law. Public Records are defined as all writings made or maintained by a state institution, such as Colorado
Mesa University, regardless of medium or format. Personal information provided to the College may be subject to public
inspection and copying unless protected by state or federal law.
Family Education Rights and Privacy Act (20 U.S.C. § 1232g)
Colorado Mesa University also complies with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA), which generally
prohibits the release of students’ education records without consent. However, Colorado Mesa University may release
student directory information or student educational records if allowed or required by FERPA. For more information
about FERPA, contact the Registrar’s Office
Information Collected
It is Colorado Mesa University’s practice to collect the least amount of personally identifiable information necessary to
fulfill its required duties and responsibilities, complete a particular transaction, deliver services, or as required by law.
This applies to all personally identifiable information regardless of medium or source.
For site administration functions, information, other than personal information linked to particular individual, is
collected for analysis and statistical purposes. Such information may include may include user visit logs, network traffic
logs and small text files known as “cookies”. This information is used to help diagnose problems, analyze site usage,
access system performance, better plan our website to meet users needs, and for marketing purposes. Information
collected and information you provide to us may result in follow-up communications.
Individuals may choose whether or not to provide personal information to Colorado Mesa University via the Internet. If
you choose not to provide the personal information we request, you can still visit most of Colorado Mesa University’s

web pages, but you may be unable to access certain options, offers, and services that involve our interaction with you.
You can opt out of the use of cookies by having your browser disable cookies or warn you before accepting a cookie.
Some Colorado Mesa University website pages allow users to request information from the College. These information
request sites require users to provide contact information as well as information about their interest in Colorado Mesa
University. Contact information is used to send information about Colorado Mesa University to the customer requesting
that information. Customer interest information is collected to determine what information the customer wishes to be
sent. You can choose NOT to provide this information online and instead call Colorado Mesa University to request that
information be sent to you.
Some of our sites also allow users to provide feedback to Colorado Mesa University. Our survey sites, such as feedback
forms on the website and MAVzone, the student and faculty portal, request users to provide contact information as
well. The contact information that's collected is used to contact the website user, if necessary. Opt-out policy: You can
choose NOT to disclose contact information when you submit survey information to us. However, if your comments
require follow-up by a member of the College, we will be unable to do so when contact information is not available.
Third Party Services
On Colorado Mesa University’s behalf, third parties may provide certain services available on Colorado Mesa University’s
web site. Colorado Mesa University may provide information, including personal information, collected over the Internet
to third party providers to help us deliver programs, products, information, and services. We will take reasonable steps
to ensure that these third party service providers are obligated to protect personal information on our behalf.
Disclaimer
The information provided in this privacy statement should not be construed as giving business, legal, or other advice, or
as warranting the security of information provided through the Colorado Mesa University web site. The Colorado Mesa
University web site contains links to many external web sites. Colorado Mesa University is not responsible for the
privacy practices or policies or the content of those external web sites.
Comments and Feedback
Please send comments, questions or concerns to webmaster@coloradomesa.edu. When sending us comments, please
include a current email address.
